<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wi-Fi sniffer on Nishant Rodrigues</title><link>/tags/wi-fi-sniffer/</link><description>Recent content in Wi-Fi sniffer on Nishant Rodrigues</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:50:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/wi-fi-sniffer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smart lighting for Large Public Spaces</title><link>/publications/smart_lighting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:50:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/publications/smart_lighting/</guid><description>This paper proposes an IoT based solution to automate smart lighting in large public spaces. The proposed solution aims to optimize power efficiency and cost effectiveness while providing an automated solution. The system makes use of devices that can detect Wi-Fi signals (Wi-Fi sniffers) from mobile devices. Continuously monitoring the smart devices (connected to a wireless network) in the vicinity makes it possible to estimate the position and number of people in an area based on the range of the device and use this to control the lighting.</description><content>&lt;p>This paper proposes an IoT based solution to automate smart lighting in large public spaces. The proposed solution aims to optimize power efficiency and cost effectiveness while providing an automated solution. The system makes use of devices that can detect Wi-Fi signals (Wi-Fi sniffers) from mobile devices. Continuously monitoring the smart devices (connected to a wireless network) in the vicinity makes it possible to estimate the position and number of people in an area based on the range of the device and use this to control the lighting. The paper illustrates the use of such devices in two settings; opening various sections of a space based on the number of people and automated lighting based on the movement of people in a large area.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>