<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications on Nishant Rodrigues</title><link>/publications/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on Nishant Rodrigues</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 15:45:06 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smart lighting for Large Public Spaces</title><link>/publications/smart_lighting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:50:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/publications/smart_lighting/</guid><description>This paper proposes an IoT based solution to automate smart lighting in large public spaces. The proposed solution aims to optimize power efficiency and cost effectiveness while providing an automated solution. The system makes use of devices that can detect Wi-Fi signals (Wi-Fi sniffers) from mobile devices. Continuously monitoring the smart devices (connected to a wireless network) in the vicinity makes it possible to estimate the position and number of people in an area based on the range of the device and use this to control the lighting.</description><content>&lt;p>This paper proposes an IoT based solution to automate smart lighting in large public spaces. The proposed solution aims to optimize power efficiency and cost effectiveness while providing an automated solution. The system makes use of devices that can detect Wi-Fi signals (Wi-Fi sniffers) from mobile devices. Continuously monitoring the smart devices (connected to a wireless network) in the vicinity makes it possible to estimate the position and number of people in an area based on the range of the device and use this to control the lighting. The paper illustrates the use of such devices in two settings; opening various sections of a space based on the number of people and automated lighting based on the movement of people in a large area.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Dilated CNN for Brain Tumor Detection</title><link>/publications/brain_tumor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 13:34:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/publications/brain_tumor/</guid><description>Brain tumor classification is a challenging task in the field of medical image processing. Technology has now enabled medical doctors to have additional aid for diagnosis. We aim to classify brain tumors using MRI images, which were collected from anonymous patients and artificial brain simulators. In this article, we carry out a comparative study between Simple Artificial Neural Networks with dropout, Basic Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), and Dilated Convolutional Neural Networks.</description><content>&lt;p>Brain tumor classification is a challenging task in the field of medical image processing. Technology has now enabled medical doctors to have additional aid for diagnosis. We aim to classify brain tumors using MRI images, which were collected from anonymous patients and artificial brain simulators. In this article, we carry out a comparative study between Simple Artificial Neural Networks with dropout, Basic Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), and Dilated Convolutional Neural Networks. The experimental results shed light on the high classification performance (accuracy 97%) of Dilated CNN. On the other hand, Dilated CNN suffers from the gridding phenomenon. An incremental, even number dilation rate takes advantage of the reduced computational overhead and also overcomes the adverse effects of gridding. Comparative analysis between different combinations of dilation rates for the different convolution layers, help validate the results. The computational overhead in terms of efficiency for training the model to reach an acceptable threshold accuracy of 90% is another parameter to compare the model performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2076-3417/10/14/4915/htm">Full paper&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;details >
&lt;summary>Cite&lt;/summary>
&lt;div class="markdown-inner">
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-bibtex" data-lang="bibtex">&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">@Article&lt;/span>{app10144915,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">AUTHOR&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{Roy, Sanjiban Sekhar and Rodrigues, Nishant and Taguchi, Y-h.}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">TITLE&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{Incremental Dilations Using CNN for Brain Tumor Classification}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">JOURNAL&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{Applied Sciences}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">VOLUME&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{10}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">YEAR&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{2020}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">NUMBER&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{14}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">ARTICLE-NUMBER&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{4915}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">URL&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{https://www.mdpi.com/2076-3417/10/14/4915}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">ISSN&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{2076-3417}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">DOI&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{10.3390/app10144915}&lt;/span>
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/details></content></item><item><title>Archive-based Swarms</title><link>/publications/fabso/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 13:30:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>/publications/fabso/</guid><description>The Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) algorithm updates each individual&amp;rsquo;s velocity and position using its own prior best position and the best position found so far by any particle. Effective search for global optima can benefit if each particle may utilize additional historical information regarding the quality of previously visited positions in its proximity. We present an approach for doing so, using an archive containing some prior particle positions, analogous to the archive used in some multi-objective optimization algorithms.</description><content>&lt;p>The Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) algorithm updates each individual&amp;rsquo;s velocity and position using its own prior best position and the best position found so far by any particle. Effective search for global optima can benefit if each particle may utilize additional historical information regarding the quality of previously visited positions in its proximity. We present an approach for doing so, using an archive containing some prior particle positions, analogous to the archive used in some multi-objective optimization algorithms. A specific instance of this approach is the proposed Fitness-Distance-Ratio Archive-Based Swarm Optimization algorithm, shown to outperform PSO and three other variants, when applied to high-dimensional neural network training problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3377929.3398112">Full paper&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;details >
&lt;summary>Cite&lt;/summary>
&lt;div class="markdown-inner">
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-bibtex" data-lang="bibtex">&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">@inproceedings&lt;/span>{10.1145/3377929.3398112,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">author&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{Rodrigues, Nishant and Mohan, Chilukuri}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">title&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{Archive-Based Swarms}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">year&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{2020}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">isbn&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{9781450371278}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">publisher&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{Association for Computing Machinery}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">address&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{New York, NY, USA}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">url&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{https://doi.org/10.1145/3377929.3398112}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">doi&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{10.1145/3377929.3398112}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">booktitle&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{Proceedings of the 2020 Genetic and
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">Evolutionary Computation Conference Companion}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">pages&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{1460–1467}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">numpages&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{8}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">keywords&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{artificial neural networks, fitness-distance ratio, archive,
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">swarm intelligence, evolutionary machine learning,
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">particle swarm optimization, premature convergence}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">location&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{Canc\&amp;#39;{u}n, Mexico}&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">series&lt;/span> = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">{GECCO &amp;#39;20}&lt;/span>
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/details></content></item></channel></rss>